[Waco] Memorial Baptist Church records, Inclusive: 1943-2003, undated, Bulk: 1943-2003
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
[Waco] Memorial Baptist Church records
Inclusive: 1943-2003, undated, Bulk: 1943-2003
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
3521
Memorial Baptist Church
8 document boxes and 5 oversized boxes.
The [Waco] Memorial Baptist Church records consist of the church's correspondence, financial, legal, and scrapbook materials, from the inception of the church to its closing.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Good.
Biography/Profile
Memorial Baptist Church, located in Waco, Texas, was established in 1943 May by a group consisting of Sunday School teachers, officers, deacons, and other Waco citizens. The name “Memorial Baptist Church” was chosen to commemorate the fallen soldiers of World War II and served as a memorial for fallen soldiers who had fought for the United States. Although the church did not initially have an official building, the Memorial Baptist Church congregation held their meetings and conducted their Sunday School classes and services in various church member’s homes. The first pastor of Waco Memorial Baptist Church was Reverend A. Meyers and shortly after he was installed, the church purchased the building and grounds at 801 South 22nd Street, Waco, Texas. The members of the church donated money to fund part of the purchase. The first meeting at this site occurred on 1943 June 27, which was conducted under the tent tabernacle purchased by the church. Three months later under the supervision of D.B. Wiley, the construction of the auditorium commenced and completed later that year. At the end of the church’s first year of operation, the Sunday School enrollment had grown from 63 to 308 participants.
Memorial Baptist Church celebrated its first anniversary on 1944 May 7 with 272 individuals present. In 1949 February, J.M. Rickerson presented to the congregation a Hammond organ as a gift. Later on 1951 July 4, due to the increasing congregation member numbers and Sunday school participants, the church voted to erect an additional education building on the ground to utilize for the growing Sunday School classes.
On 1960 April 1, the church purchased the final site for Memorial Baptist Church at 2218 Ross Avenue. A new auditorium was dedicated on 1960 October 23 to serve a total church membership of 1,100. Due to the continuing expanding membership of church, the building facing 22nd Street was later purchased as an addition and was converted into a Youth Building.
On 2002 December 31, Waco Memorial Baptist church closed due to dwindling membership, but the church still had sufficient funds to continue to operate. When Memorial Baptist Church purchased the land for their final site, the neighborhood was predominately a Caucasian neighborhood and slowly evolved into a predominately Hispanic neighborhood. The church failed to attract the newer area residents, resulting in gradually diminishing numbers. The church and grounds eventually were donated to the Waco Baptist Association of which the church was a participating member. The church and grounds continued to be used as a church and now is Maranatha Church, a member of Waco Baptist Association. In the church’s 59 year history, the church was led by seven pastors, A. Meyers, Harry Brasher, B. Gene Grace, Joe Cranfill, Kenneth Dill, Derek Dodson and finally Jimmie Spann.
Scope and Content
The [Waco] Memorial Baptist Church records are comprised of minutes from various aspects of the church including the minutes for business, deacons, the building and grounds committee, the youth council, and the senior citizens group, the “Trailblazers.” In addition to these minutes are notes from multiple committees such as the fellowship committee, educational committee, and publicity committee. There are also detailed financial reports concerning the general operations of the church dating from 1961-2002. These financial reports include information detailing the financial business of the church, lists of the death of the members of the congregations, donation records, financial and detailed information regarding various mission works, receipts, notes for banking and church expenditures, correspondence concerning insurance. Also included is the Memorial Baptist Church constitution, a list of the church policies, and job descriptions. There is also detailed information concerning the various preachers of Waco Memorial Baptist Church, a brief history of the establishment of the church, lists of the charter members, listings of members and membership dues, Sunday school reports, lists of various goals for the church, schedules, invitations, RSVP cards, programs, thank you notes, and notes for preparing for special celebratory services such as the Homecoming service in 1983 and the 45th anniversary services. In addition to the general church business there is also more specific information concerning the Memorial Youth Council, also known as “Youth for Christ”, such as the history of the group, various newsletters, bulletins and the youth council constitution. There are also photographs of the early meeting places of the Waco Memorial Baptist Church congregations, church events, and church members. Finally, the collection includes the church ledgers, scrapbooks, and membership cards. All of the collections contents date 1943-2003.
Arrangement
The [Waco] Memorial Baptist Church records were extremely well organized prior to processing. The boxes were arranged with the minutes from each division of the church followed by Financial Reports and other documents concerning the church history and day to day activities. Lastly, the membership cards were organized in chronological order. The [Waco] Memorial Baptist Church records is now arranged in six series. Series I. Correspondence, Series II. Legal Documents, Series III. Financial Documents, Series IV. Literary Productions, Series V. Scrapbooks, Series VI. Photographic Materials. Series II. Legal Documents has 5 subseries, I. Minutes- Business, II. Minutes-Deacons, III. Minutes-Trailblazers, IV. Church Records, and V. Constitutions. Series III. Financial Documents has two subseries, I. Reports, II. Ledgers. Series IV. Literary Productions has 3 subseries, I. Special Events, II. Church Life, and III. Church Bulletins.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 3521. Acquired 2003-01-00
Related Resources
Related references
“Member Churches”. Waco Regional Baptist Association. 2012. Web. Accessed on 2012 November 2.
Ryan, Terri Jo. “Saying goodbye to Waco church; Sunday service will be the last for congregation with dwindling numbers.” Waco Tribune, 2002 December 28.
Index Terms
Subjects
Baptists -- Texas -- History.; Baptists -- Texas -- Waco.; Baptists -- Texas.; City churches -- Texas -- Waco.; Waco (Tex.) -- Church history.
Genres
Correspondence.; Essays.; Financial records.; Minutes (Records); Photographs.; Programs.; Scrapbooks.
- Correspondence, 1944-2003; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Good.
  Biography/Profile
  This series contains the correspondence produced by the Waco Memorial Baptist Church. Included are the letters from the church to the Old Church Association which details general information about the church and correspondence that was written in 2003, when the church was closed and the grounds were donated. The materials are in good condition.
  - Old Church Association Letters (1 of 2), 1944-1959 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Old Church Association Letters (2 of 2), 1944-1959 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Old Church Association Letters (1 of 2), 1960-1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Old Church Association Letters (2 of 2), 1960-1970 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - General, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Legal, 1943-2002; 2
  This series contains the legal documents of Waco Memorial Baptist Church. These documents include the minutes from the business meetings, minutes from the deacons meetings, minutes from the buildings and grounds meetings, minutes from the Youth Council meetings and finally the minutes from the “Trailblazers” Senior Citizens meetings. Also included are the constitutions for the Waco Memorial Baptist Church and Youth Council. The materials are in good condition.
  - Minutes, Business: 1943 April 14-1954 August 11 (1 of 11) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, Business: 1943 April 14-1954 August 11 (2 of 11) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, Business: 1943 April 14-1954 August 11 (3 of 11) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, Business: 1943 April 14-1954 August 11 (4 of 11) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, Business: 1943 April 14-1954 August 11 (5 of 11) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, Business: 1943 April 14-1954 August 11 (6 of 11) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Minutes, Business: 1943 April 14-1954 August 11 (7 of 11) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Minutes, Business: 1943 April 14-1954 August 11 (8 of 11) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Minutes, Business: 1943 April 14-1954 August 11 (9 of 11) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Minutes, Business: 1943 April 14-1954 August 11 (10 of 11) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Minutes, Business: 1943 April 14-1954 August 11 (11 of 11) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Minutes, Business: 1951 April 11-1957 December 4 (1 of 11) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Minutes, Business: 1951 April 11-1957 December 4 (2 of 11) (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Minutes, Business: 1951 April 11-1957 December 4 (3 of 11) (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Minutes, Business: 1951 April 11-1957 December 4 (4 of 11) (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Minutes, Business: 1951 April 11-1957 December 4 (5 of 11) (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Minutes, Business: 1951 April 11-1957 December 4 (6 of 11) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Minutes, Business: 1951 April 11-1957 December 4 (7 of 11) (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Minutes, Business: 1951 April 11-1957 December 4 (8 of 11) (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Minutes, Business: 1951 April 11-1957 December 4 (9 of 11) (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Minutes, Business: 1951 April 11-1957 December 4 (10 of 11) (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Minutes, Business: 1951 April 11-1957 December 4 (11 of 11) (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Minutes, Business: 1957 December 22-1961 August 9 (1 of 7) (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Minutes, Business: 1957 December 22-1961 August 9 (2 of 7) (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Minutes, Business: 1957 December 22-1961 August 9 (3 of 7) (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Minutes, Business: 1957 December 22-1961 August 9 (4 of 7) (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Minutes, Business: 1957 December 22-1961 August 9 (5 of 7) (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Minutes, Business: 1957 December 22-1961 August 9 (6 of 7) (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Minutes, Business: 1957 December 22-1961 August 9 (7 of 7) (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Minutes, Business: 1956 January 5-1963 September 4 (1 of 6) (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Minutes, Business: 1956 January 5-1963 September 4 (2 of 6) (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Minutes, Business: 1956 January 5-1963 September 4 (3 of 6) (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Minutes, Business: 1956 January 5-1963 September 4 (4 of 6) (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Minutes, Business: 1956 January 5-1963 September 4 (5 of 6) (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Minutes, Business: 1956 January 5-1963 September 4 (6 of 6) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, Business: 1961 September 13-1966 January 30 (1 of 7) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, Business: 1961 September 13-1966 January 30 (2 of 7) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, Business: 1961 September 13-1966 January 30 (3 of 7) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, Business: 1961 September 13-1966 January 30 (4 of 7) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, Business: 1961 September 13-1966 January 30 (5 of 7) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, Business: 1961 September 13-1966 January 30 (6 of 7) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, Business: 1961 September 13-1966 January 30 (7 of 7) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, Business: 1963 October 9-1968 August 7 (1 of 4) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, Business: 1963 October 9-1968 August 7 (2 of 4) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, Business: 1963 October 9-1968 August 7 (3 of 4) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Minutes, Business: 1963 October 9-1968 August 7 (4 of 4) (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Minutes, Business: 1966 February 9-1970 August 12 (1 of 6) (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Minutes, Business: 1966 February 9-1970 August 12 (2 of 6) (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Minutes, Business: 1966 February 9-1970 August 12 (3 of 6) (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Minutes, Business: 1966 February 9-1970 August 12 (4 of 6) (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Minutes, Business: 1966 February 9-1970 August 12 (5 of 6) (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Minutes, Business: 1966 February 9-1970 August 12 (6 of 6) (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Minutes, Business: 1970 September 23-1971 September 15 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Minutes, Business: 1973 October 10-1975 June 4 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Minutes, Business: 1975 August 6-1981 March 8 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Minutes, Business: 1981 April 8-1986 October 8 (1 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Minutes, Business: 1981 April 8-1986 October 8 (2 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Minutes, Business: 1981 April 8-1986 October 8 (3 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Minutes, Business: 1987 January 7-1989 December 31 (1 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Minutes, Business: 1987 January 7-1989 December 31 (2 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Minutes, Business: 1987 January 7-1989 December 31 (3 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Minutes, Business: 1990 January 10-1994 December 18 (1 of 4) (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Minutes, Business: 1990 January 10-1994 December 18 (2 of 4) (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Minutes, Business: 1990 January 10-1994 December 18 (3 of 4) (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Minutes, Business: 1990 January 10-1994 December 18 (4 of 4) (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Minutes, Business: 1995 January 11-2002 December 8 (1 of 6) (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Minutes, Business: 1995 January 11-2002 December 8 (2 of 6) (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Minutes, Business: 1995 January 11-2002 December 8 (3 of 6) (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Minutes, Business: 1995 January 11-2002 December 8 (4 of 6) (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Minutes, Business: 1995 January 11-2002 December 8 (5 of 6) (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Minutes, Business: 1995 January 11-2002 December 8 (6 of 6) (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Minutes, Deacons: undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1947 September 7-1950 April 2 (1 of 4) (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1947 September 7-1950 April 2 (2 of 4) (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1947 September 7-1950 April 2 (3 of 4) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1947 September 7-1950 April 2 (4 of 4) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Minutes Deacons: 1950 June 4-1951 September 2 (1 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Minutes Deacons: 1950 June 4-1951 September 2 (2 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Minutes Deacons: 1950 June 4-1951 September 2 (3 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1951 October 7-1953 June 7 (1 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1951 October 7-1953 June 7 (2 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1951 October 7-1953 June 7 (3 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1953 September 6-1954 October 3 (1 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1953 September 6-1954 October 3 (2 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1953 September 6-1954 October 3 (3 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1954 November 7-1955 September 4 (1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1954 November 7-1955 September 4 (2 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1955 November 6-1956 June 10 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1956 July 1-1957 April 7 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1957 May 6-1957 December 8 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1958 January 5-1958 May 4 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1958 June 1-1958 December 14 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1959 January 4-1959 August 2 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1959 September 5-1960 May 26 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1960 June 5-1963 October 6 (1 of 4) (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1960 June 5-1963 October 6 (2 of 4) (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1960 June 5-1963 October 6 (3 of 4) (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1960 June 5-1963 October 6 (4 of 4) (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1963 November 3-1966 March 6 (1 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1963 November 3-1966 March 6 (2 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1963 November 3-1966 March 6 (3 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1966 April 3-1967 June 4 (1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1966 April 3-1967 June 4 (2 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1967 July 2-1969 April 6 (1 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1967 July 2-1969 April 6 (2 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1967 July 2-1969 April 6 (3 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1969 May 11-1969 July 6 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1971 October 4-1976 November 9 (1 of 5) (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1971 October 4-1976 November 9 (2 of 5) (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1971 October 4-1976 November 9 (3 of 5) (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1971 October 4-1976 November 9 (4 of 5) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1971 October 4-1976 November 9 (5 of 5) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1977 October 4-1982 March 29 (1 of 7) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1977 October 4-1982 March 29 (2 of 7) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1977 October 4-1982 March 29 (3 of 7) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1977 October 4-1982 March 29 (4 of 7) (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1977 October 4-1982 March 29 (5 of 7) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1977 October 4-1982 March 29 (6 of 7) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1977 October 4-1982 March 29 (7 of 7) (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1982 April 6-1986 September 9 (1 of 4) (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1982 April 6-1986 September 9 (2 of 4) (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1982 April 6-1986 September 9 (3 of 4) (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1982 April 6-1986 September 9 (4 of 4) (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Minutes, Deacons: 1986 October 7-1992 March 3 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Minutes Deacons: 1992 April 7-2002 December 5 (1 of 8) (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Minutes Deacons: 1992 April 7-2002 December 5 (2 of 8) (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Minutes Deacons: 1992 April 7-2002 December 5 (3 of 8) (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Minutes Deacons: 1992 April 7-2002 December 5 (4 of 8) (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Minutes Deacons: 1992 April 7-2002 December 5 (5 of 8) (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Minutes Deacons: 1992 April 7-2002 December 5 (6 of 8) (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Minutes Deacons: 1992 April 7-2002 December 5 (7 of 8) (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Minutes Deacons: 1992 April 7-2002 December 5 (8 of 8) (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Minutes, Buildings and Grounds: 1979 January 25-1980 August 12 (1 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Minutes, Buildings and Grounds: 1979 January 25-1980 August 12 (2 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Minutes, Buildings and Grounds: 1984 July 11-1991 January 15 (1 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Minutes, Buildings and Grounds: 1984 July 11-1991 January 15 (2 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Minutes, Buildings and Grounds: 1980 October 14-1983 April 12 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Minutes, Youth Council, 1962-1971 (1 of 6) (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Minutes, Youth Council, 1962-1971 (2 of 6) (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Minutes, Youth Council, 1962-1971 (3 of 6) (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Minutes, Youth Council, 1962-1971 (4 of 6) (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Minutes, Youth Council, 1962-1971 (5 of 6) (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Minutes, Youth Council, 1962-1971 (6 of 6) (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Minutes, “Trailblazers”, Senior Citizens: 1977 September 29-1981 November (1 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Minutes, “Trailblazers”, Senior Citizens: 1977 September 29-1981 November (2 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Minutes, “Trailblazers”, Senior Citizens: 1977 September 29-1981 November (3 of 3) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, “Trailblazers”, Senior Citizens: 1983 January 27-1987 October 29 (1 of 3) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, “Trailblazers”, Senior Citizens: 1983 January 27-1987 October 29 (2 of 3) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, “Trailblazers”, Senior Citizens: 1983 January 27-1987 October 29 (3 of 3) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, “Trailblazers”, Senior Citizens: 1988 January 28-1994 October 27 (1 of 4) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, “Trailblazers”, Senior Citizens: 1988 January 28-1994 October 27 (2 of 4) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, “Trailblazers”, Senior Citizens: 1988 January 28-1994 October 27 (3 of 4) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, “Trailblazers”, Senior Citizens: 1988 January 28-1994 October 27 (4 of 4) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Church Records (1 of 6), 1943-1944 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Church Records (2 of 6), 1943-1944 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Church Records (3 of 6), 1943-1944 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Church Records (4 of 6), 1943-1944 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Church Records (5 of 6), 1943-1944 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Church Records (6 of 6), 1943-1944 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Youth Council, 1962-1973 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Constitution of Memorial Baptist Church (1 of 3), 1990 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Constitution of Memorial Baptist Church (2 of 3), 1990 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Constitution of Memorial Baptist Church (3 of 3), 1900 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Financial, 1953-2002; 3
  This series contains the financial documents of the Waco Memorial Baptist Church. These financial documents include annual reports, budgets, financial reports, and the church’s ledgers from 1967-1991. The materials are in good condition.
  - Reports, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Reports (1 of 2), 1957 March-1959 June (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Reports (2 of 2), 1957 March-1959 June (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Reports (1 of 3), 1961-1964 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Reports (2 of 3), 1961-1964 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Reports (3 of 3), 1961-1964 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Reports (1 of 4), 1965-1969 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Reports (2 of 4), 1965-1969 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Reports (3 of 4), 1965-1969 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Reports (4 of 4), 1965-1969 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Reports, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Reports (1 of 2), 1976-1979 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Reports (2 of 2), 1976-1979 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Reports (1 of 3), 1980-1984 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Reports (2 of 3), 1980-1984 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Reports (3 of 3), 1980-1984 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Reports (1 of 6), 1985-1989 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Reports (2 of 6), 1985-1989 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Reports (3 of 6), 1985-1989 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Reports (4 of 6), 1985-1989 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Reports (5 of 6), 1985-1989 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Reports (6 of 6), 1985-1989 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Reports (1 of 5), 1990-1994 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Reports (2 of 5), 1990-1994 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Reports (3 of 5), 1990-1994 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Reports (4 of 5), 1990-1994 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Reports (5 of 5), 1990-1994 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Reports (1 of 4), 1995-1994 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Reports (2 of 4), 1995-1994 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Reports (3 of 4), 1995-1994 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Reports (4 of 4), 1995-1994 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Reports (1 of 3), 2000-2002 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Reports (2 of 3), 2000-2002 (Box 6, Folder 14)